<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PraxisLIVE Unofficial Guide</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PraxisLIVE Unofficial Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 16:59:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial_1_Av</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorial_1_av/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 16:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorial_1_av/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone! So, it seems that our introduction got your attention! You&amp;rsquo;ll be glad to know that a new part of our basic series is ready! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started! Click here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1 - Our first project</title>
      <link>/tutorials/tutorial_0001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 21:43:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/tutorial_0001/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this second part of this PraxisLIVE tutorial series! In this new episode we&amp;rsquo;re going to install the software, start a new project and play a little with some nodes.
SETUP
Regardless your OS (Windows, MacOS or Linux, just go to the website and download the software. Just for Linux, if your distro is not Debian-based, you have to install dpkg on your system and run the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 0 Available!</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorial_0_av/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 19:38:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorial_0_av/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re glad to announce that the first PraxisLIVE tutorial is available here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 0 – Introduction</title>
      <link>/tutorials/tutorial_0000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 16:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/tutorial_0000/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this basic tutorial series about PraxisLIVE. In this first episode, you&amp;rsquo;ll be introduced to the software and what are its possibles usages.
PraxisLIVE is an open source software for artists to create advanced multimedia content (for example video mappings, audio-syncronized visuals created with code, or GUIs to manage MIDI sounds). Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of its key features:
 intuitive graphical patching, so it works with nodes written in Processing, a Java-based scripting language; You can modify the project and nodes values while running it; Real-time audio/video (it uses infact OpenGL, GStreamer, JACK); It can manage MIDI, OSC, GUIs and physical computing, which are computers that are able to translate real world signals, like sounds or movements, as an input; It&amp;rsquo;s cross-platform (Windows, MacOS, Linux and even Raspberry Pi!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 15:19:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/about/</guid>
      <description>This is an unofficial guide for PraxisLIVE that will help newcomers to manage the software basics. In the future custom nodes that will improve the software capabilities will be uploaded here. Here are the references to the official PraxisLIVE material.
PraxisLIVE: https://www.praxislive.org/
PraxisLIVE Documentation: https://docs.praxislive.org/
PraxisLIVE GitHub: https://github.com/praxis-live
Processing: https://processing.org/
This project is developped by Giacomo Sabatini and professor Davide Riboli at the Urbino Accademy of Fine Arts.
All the contents are under the MIT License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo</title>
      <link>/posts/demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 14:23:33 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/demo/</guid>
      <description>Made with this tutorial:
   this is a blockquote
 &amp;lt;h6&amp;gt; This is how to highlight some code &amp;lt;/h6&amp;gt; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to PraxisLIVE Unofficial Guide</title>
      <link>/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 13:55:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>We are glad to open this blog, which will host info, updates, guides and new nodes developped by us!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>