<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Giacomo Sabatini on PraxisLIVE Unofficial Guide</title>
    <link>/authors/giacomo-sabatini/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Giacomo Sabatini on PraxisLIVE Unofficial Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 21:10:08 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/giacomo-sabatini/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 4 Available!</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorial_4_av/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 21:10:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorial_4_av/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone! The third episode about Audio-Reactive Visuals is available right now! Click here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 4 - One GUI to rule them all</title>
      <link>/tutorials/tutorial_0004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 10:23:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/tutorial_0004/</guid>
      <description>Hello there! We got to the final chapter of our PraxisLIVE basic series (excluding the extra chapter)! Today we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the GUI patch, which you might find very useful if you are going to show your work at a live event. The title, a semi-quote from &amp;ldquo;The Lord of the Rings&amp;rdquo;, sums what GUI do: it allows you to control live parameters all in one screen very quickly, without switching between all the nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming website upgrades and extra episode!</title>
      <link>/posts/website-extra-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 22:38:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/website-extra-announcement/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to announce that when the basic tutorial series will be over, I&amp;rsquo;ll add a plugin called Disqus, which will allow you on all my posts and tutorials to comment and let me know your thoughts and advices (or doubts if something wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear). The other new is that an extra episode about other little things I might have left and that will improve our project. By the way I will create a GitHub repository that will store all the projects made here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 3 Available!</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorial_3_av/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 22:28:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorial_3_av/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone! The third episode about Audio-Reactive Visuals is available right now! Click here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 3 - Audio-reactive visuals</title>
      <link>/tutorials/tutorial_0003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 16:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/tutorial_0003/</guid>
      <description>Hello everybody! We&amp;rsquo;re getting to the final steps of this PraxisLIVE basic tutorial series! Today we&amp;rsquo;re about to see the &amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; of this software: how to create audio on PraxisLIVE? How to make interact Processing visuals with an audio input?
Let&amp;rsquo;s open as usual our project, but this time by also creating a new file (Audio Patch). Once done, you&amp;rsquo;ll see, like on video one when we created it, only the output node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2 Available!</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorial_2_av/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 23:45:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorial_2_av/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone! I&amp;rsquo;m sorry if this episode came a bit late, I had to transfer from Manjaro to Windows 10 and it shall be temporary. To recover the time lost, this episode will cover parts of what should have been in the third one. Let&amp;rsquo;s go! Click here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 2 - Let&#39;s start coding!</title>
      <link>/tutorials/tutorial_0002/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 09:44:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/tutorial_0002/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this second episode of the basic tutorial about PraxisLIVE! Today we&amp;rsquo;ll be starting coding with Processing, tasting a little bit what it&amp;rsquo;s capable of!
Let&amp;rsquo;s re-open our last project: you should have it displayed on the left. Then click on the gear near to the play button to Build the project. Once done, you should see again your video file opened.
First of all, we shall edit the animator node to make it loop</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1 Available!</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorial_1_av/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 16:59:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorial_1_av/</guid>
      <description>Hello, everyone! So, it seems that our introduction got your attention! You&amp;rsquo;ll be glad to know that a new part of our basic series is ready! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started! Click here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 1 - Our first project</title>
      <link>/tutorials/tutorial_0001/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 21:43:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/tutorial_0001/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this second part of this PraxisLIVE tutorial series! In this new episode we&amp;rsquo;re going to install the software, start a new project and play a little with some nodes.
SETUP
Regardless your OS (Windows, MacOS or Linux), just go to the website and download the software. Just for Linux, if your distro is not Debian-based, you have to install dpkg on your system and run the following command:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 0 Available!</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorial_0_av/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 19:38:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorial_0_av/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re glad to announce that the first PraxisLIVE tutorial is available here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial 0 – Introduction</title>
      <link>/tutorials/tutorial_0000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 16:16:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorials/tutorial_0000/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this basic tutorial series about PraxisLIVE. In this first episode, you&amp;rsquo;ll be introduced to the software and what are its possibles usages.
PraxisLIVE is an open source software for artists to create advanced multimedia content (for example video mappings, audio-syncronized visuals created with code, or GUIs to manage MIDI sounds). Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of its key features:
 intuitive graphical patching, so it works with nodes written in Processing, a Java-based scripting language; You can modify the project and nodes values while running it; Real-time audio/video (it uses infact OpenGL, GStreamer, JACK); It can manage MIDI, OSC, GUIs and physical computing, which are computers that are able to translate real world signals, like sounds or movements, as an input; It&amp;rsquo;s cross-platform (Windows, MacOS, Linux and even Raspberry Pi!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>